# **Vinicius Pasqualini Carvalho**

<u>pasqualini9@gmail.com</u> / +351 938 320 821 https://www.linkedin.com/in/viniciuspc/en - https://github.com/viniciuspc

Nationality: Brazilian and Portuguese

#### Researcher

Proactive and responsible Back-End Developer focused on Web Systems. Know for strong technical knowledge, deliver reliable systems, and do good teamwork. More than six years of developing successful systems for financial institutions and research centers with excellent feedback from customers.

#### SELECTED HIGHLIGHTS

- I helped in the development of a project management system used in several research centers of Europe.
- I built a software-intensive system architecture for fraud detection, in the context of Master's in Software Engineering course at the University of Coimbra, praised by both the customer and the mentors.
- I improved user experience by refactoring existing Web Systems to use recent technologies such as Spring and JQuery.

KEY COMPETENCES	
Software Engineering	Software Architecture
Programing	Project Management
Full-stack development	Agile Methodologies

#### EDUCATION

"Universidade de Coimbra", Coimbra, Portugal Master's in Software Engineer 2018/2019-2019/2020

"Faculdade de Informatica e Administracao Paulista" (FIAP), Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil Master of Business Administration (MBA), Java Application Development– SOA 2013-2014

"Faculdade de Informatica e Administracao Paulista" (FIAP), Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems 2009-2012

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Fraunhofer Portugal AICOS/Porto, Portugal/ July 2020 - Present Scientist

The Fraunhofer Portugal is a non-profit private association founded by Fraunhofer-Gesellschaft, the largest organization for applied research in Europe.

- I am part of a team developing a project management system using Ruby on Rails, React.Js, and Java Script.
- Helped the delivery of the system using docker containers.

## Elin Duxus/Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil/ January 2016 – July 2017 Java Developer

Elin Duxus is a Brazilian consultant that builds solutions targeting the financial market.

- I led a team with two more professionals to successfully deliver high-quality Web Systems in Java, following agile methodologies like Scrum.
- I created and defined activities to be scheduled at the product backlog by me, in meetings with the Product Owner.
- I improved user experience by refactoring existing Web Systems to use recent technologies such as Spring and JQuery.

### Elin Duxus/Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil/ January 2013 – December 2015 Junior Java Developer

- I developed a server-side Java graph generator to be used by four other systems.
- I helped to implement Scrum in the company.
- I implemented a binary classification algorithm based on Naive Bayes, to determine if the news has a good or bad impact on the reputation of an organization, a person, or a product.

Elin Duxus/Sao Paulo (SP), Brazil/ July 2011 – December 2012 Java Developer Intern

LANGUAGES	
Portuguese – Native	English - Upper-Intermediate (B2)

## **COURSES AND CERTIFICATES**

- CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence; EDX
  The Complete Ruby on Rails Developer; Udemy
  Modern React with Redux [2020 Update]: Udemy

ADDITIONAL CREDENTIALS	
TECHNICAL SKILLS	Ruby on Rails / Java / Hibernate / GIT / Spring / JQuery / CSS3 / HTML5 / JavaScript / / React.JS / Scrum / Oracle / MySql / SQL Server / HSQLDB / Eclipse / Junit / Mockito / Tomcat / Linux / Test Driven Development / Apache Flink / Redis / Software Architecture
HOBBIES AND INTEREST	<ul><li>Play video games.</li><li>Build personal computers.</li></ul>